He said, "Listen, if you're a
Republican, vote for governor of
Florida, consider James Fishback,
February 2026." That was you.
>> Yeah, that was my assistant.
>> [music]
[music]
>> All right, so Mehdi Hasan did an
interview with this guy John Kiriakou. I
covered him the other day in his
conversation with Theo Von. This guy's
been going viral. He's an ex-CIA officer
who exposed the torture program, went to
jail for a couple years, and then got
out, and then like blew up on TikTok
bizarrely, and had a career before that.
He was writing books, he was doing TED
Talks, etc. So, most of his advocacy
since leaving the CIA and doing the
whole whistleblower thing has been
anti-CIA or at least like critical of
the CIA. But, I think, you know, anytime
you have a guy like this, there's
there's cause for concern, and there's
just a little bit of confusion or some
things that don't quite add up about
this guy's ideology. Namely, that if
he's truly anti-CIA at this point, I
don't really know where that puts him on
the political spectrum, which is
something that comes up in this
conversation a decent amount, and that's
really what I want to get into. So, in
this first part, this is Kiriakou
telling the story of when he originally
blew the whistle, etc. And already
there's some things about this that
don't quite sit right with me. So,
here's that.
>> What made you go public after all those
years of having left the CIA and taking
this big step? And explain to our
viewers what happened to you after that.
>> Sure.
I complained vociferously inside the CIA
about the torture program. I'm I'm sorry
to say that of of 14 people approached
and asked if they wanted to be trained
uh in in the use of these torture
techniques, I was the only one of the 14
who said no.
And I thought this was so clearly
illegal, immoral, unethical, [music]
somebody was going to come out and say
something, and nobody said anything. And
then in December of 2007, Brian Ross
approached me from ABC News and said
that he had a source who said that I had
tortured Abu Zubaydah, Zayn al-Abidin
Muhammad Husayn. I said, "Absolutely
untrue. I was the only person who was
ever kind to Abu Zubaydah."
And he said, "Well, you're welcome to
come on the show and defend yourself." I
didn't know that was a reporter's trick
because I'd never spoken with a reporter
before. And so, I said
>> 2007.
>> 2007. I said, "I'll think about it." In
the meantime, while I'm thinking about
it, President Bush gives a press
conference in which he looks directly in
the camera and says, "We do not
torture."
>> [music]
>> And I said to my wife, who was a senior
CIA officer, I said, "He is a bald-faced
liar. He's looking the American people
in the eye and just lying to them."
And then a couple of days later,
as he's walking to the Marine One
helicopter,
he shouts, in response to a reporter's
question, that if there is torture, it's
because of a rogue CIA officer.
>> Oh, wow.
>> And I said to my wife, "Brian Ross's
source is at the White House, and
they're going to pin this on me. I'm
going to go public." And I decided that
I would just tell the truth and let the
cards fall
>> Okay, so this whole I've never spoken
with a report I didn't know that was a
reporter's trick. He just He just got
me. He's saying that essentially this
reporter was trying to lure him into a
conversation by saying, "Well, there's a
CIA source throwing you under the bus.
So, if you want to come talk to me about
it, you can do that." He's essentially
implying that they didn't have a source
like that. And he's like, "Oh, well, I
just didn't know that they do that." I
mean, come on, that's [__] This is
high-level CIA operator. He tells plenty
of stories about [__] with the media.
So, aside from the fact that he says he
was bothered by George Bush lying about
it, he essentially says that he caught a
whiff that they were going to try to
throw him under the bus, which, if he
was making noise behind the scenes and
kind of raising attention about this,
and they needed somebody to pin it on,
it's not out of the question that they
would choose the person who has been
going against the program if they felt
like they could get away with it.
Although that's not exactly how he tells
this story. That's not really what he
said about it before. And really, in
this retelling, it sounds more like he
was paranoid that they were going to try
to pin it on him after all, and that's
why he took it public rather than it
being some kind of like moralistic
thing. So, in this next part, he talks
about recounts kind of what's happened
over the last few months where he has
become super well-known, famous on Tik
Tok, went super viral in all these
different places, and now is like a
well-known commentator cavorting with
people like Tucker Carlson and outsiders
from, you know, various parts of the
political spectrum. So, again, this is a
part that's a little bit sketchy to me,
and there's some particularly sketchy
parts about this. So, I just want to
play that real quick.
>> You've become an online personality,
don't you, John? In fact, I interviewed
you a few years ago, and even then you
weren't as big as you are now. Complex
magazine describes you as a Tik Tok
sensation with a skill for narrative
mastery. What was the moment you
realized, "Oh, I'm a bit of an online
celebrity"?
>> Well, it was about 11 weeks ago.
>> Okay.
>> I happened to be in Dubai during a
business trip, and my niece called me,
and she said, "Uncle John, you're
exploding on Tik Tok." [music] And I
said, "Why?"
And she said, "I don't know, but you're
everywhere." I said, [music] "Okay." I
thought some one-day thing, something
happened, something in the algorithm.
>> [music]
>> And I went to bed. The next day, CAA
calls me, the Creative Artists Agency.
>> They want to rep you.
>> And they said, "Tell us you're not
represented." I said, "No, I'm not
represented."
>> You are now.
>> everything just seems to happen for this
guy. He just gets swept into all these
crazy things, and he's always just like,
"Well, yes, I would like to get involved
with that." And so, he says he was on a
business trip in the Middle East in in
Dubai when he got this phone call about
the fact that he was blowing up on Tik
Tok, and he's like, "Ah, I thought it
was nothing." So, I mean, I don't know
what business trip he would have been
doing in Dubai. That's a little odd,
right? This guy does speeches, he writes
books. I don't know what business he
would be doing there, really. It's not
out of the question, little strange,
notable that one of his friends, Tucker
Carlson, somebody that he has been
involved in this sort of like
anti-government operation type of thing,
also seems to have some business ties in
the Middle East in places like Qatar and
that becoming more public, more
well-known about him seems to also
follow with his advocacy against Israel
and even for Islam or Islamic people,
Muslim people in some cases which is
never something he used to advocate for
before. So, you know, not enough details
there to really draw the connection,
just a little odd. But, I think that
there is like a lack of scrutiny this
guy has about the fact that he has
exploded so much. Even Professor Jang,
he said in his exact words when talking
to Mehdi Hasan, "I don't think it's
completely organic." Kiryakou hasn't
shown any type of scrutiny of that which
makes me a little bit more skeptical of
him. In this next part, Mehdi asked him
about the things that he's not allowed
to say and he explains why he's able to
say certain things which is a relevant
question surrounding his commentary,
certainly. So, here's that.
>> When you talk about your experience in
the CIA, I'm sure people want to hear
stories. What did you see? What did you
hear?
>> What are you restricted by? Obviously,
you don't want to go back to prison.
>> No, I don't want to go back to prison,
but over the years because I've written
so many books, I've written now nine
books,
I've gotten all my stories cleared.
Plus, the the CIA is subject to
something called the mandatory
declassification.
Information has to be declassified when
it gets [clears throat] to the 30-year
or 35-year mark. And besides, my opinion
is not classified so long as it's not
based on specifically classified
information.
>> assume that there are things that you
know that you still can't say.
>> Absolutely.
>> How bad are they?
>> Yeah, it's it's pretty ugly.
>> So, as I said in the last episode that I
did about him, it's clear that anything
he's saying on the record here is is
sanctioned speech. It's things he's
allowed to say. There's no way he would
be running around saying things the CIA
doesn't want him to say. Now, that's not
the same as expressing his opinion that
he thinks the CIA should be abolished or
whatever, which they talk about in a
second here. Whether or not he truly
believes that or whatever, him
expressing that opinion is not the same
as him saying things the CIA wouldn't
want him to about their procedures. The
idea that he got these things cleared,
he says, "All my stories are cleared
because of the books I've written over
the years." That's interesting. It
raises questions about what exactly the
process is there because based on his
narrative, the CIA hates him and they
hounded his wife at the time out of the
CIA as well. And, you know, so based on
his version of events, the CIA, I don't
see why they would clear his ability to
write these books in the first place. I
mean, some of it is probably covered by
the mandatory disclosure that he's
talking about, but some of it isn't.
And, you know, the fact that all of the
stories he would be telling in a public
sphere have been cleared behind the
scenes raises some skepticism in me,
again. But, in this next part, this is
really where I find him to be a little
bit slippery. Something that I've
noticed he does is if somebody
challenges him, or especially about
something that he like he got wrong or
you said this at one point or something,
his tactic is to just completely give
up. You're right. You're totally right.
And, he clearly does this kind of
people-pleasing thing where he's sort of
agreeing with whoever's in front of him.
And, you'll see an example of him doing
that with Mehdi Hasan here. So, this is
him saying this thing about how he
believes the CIA should be abolished,
which credit to him, he has made that
case multiple times.
>> agree with people who say the CIA is a
rogue agency that needs to be shut down?
>> Yes. I'm I'm on record as saying that I
think the CIA should be shut down. And,
you know, we've got
>> Not enough people say that, though.
>> No, not enough people
>> I mean, Democrats are too scared to say
abolish ICE. I've never
>> [laughter]
>> I've never heard the slogan abolish CIA.
Maybe we're coining it here today on
Mehdi Unfiltered. Abolish CIA. Maybe a
Democratic presidential candidate in
2028 could run on that.
>> Most countries have one intelligence
service. Some have two.
The United States has 18.
>> 18, which is currently being managed by
Tulsi Gabbard.
>> Tulsi Gabbard has
>> Okay, so two things come up here that he
instinctually agrees with Medhi about
that I'm not actually sure he really
agrees with him on because the whole
thing about abolish ICE he goes, "Yeah."
>> [laughter]
>> When Medhi brings up Democrats won't
even say abolish ICE. And I don't know
that John Kiriakou agrees with
abolishing ICE. I think if he was
talking to somebody like Tucker Carlson,
he would probably make the argument for
why some kind of immigration enforcement
or deportation is necessary or some kind
of policy that was happening under Obama
or Biden that was facilitating
immigration. He doesn't always make
right-wing points, but I have a feeling
he would kind of play the middle if that
issue were to come up with a
right-winger. Same with Tulsi Gabbard.
He has praised Tulsi Gabbard. He thinks
Tulsi Gabbard is great. So, you know,
he's just kind of automatically agreeing
with Medhi here and moving on from the
Tulsi Gabbard issue rather than making
it clear that he doesn't agree with him
on that. So, just interesting. He does
that at a couple points here. But to be
fair, he also makes this great point
about how the work of the CIA could be
and is already done by other agencies.
It's redundant and that's why there's a
case for uh abolishing it totally, which
is actually something I don't hear very
much. You do hear cases like that in
regards to ICE and maybe because of his
supposedly anti-government positions, he
[music] would fall in that camp on ICE.
I just haven't heard him say that. And
here would be another example of not
only Medhi calling him out about, you
know, sort of shaping his opinions
[music] at the time to fit who he was
talking to, but also mirroring Medhi's
opinions and viewpoint on this
perspective and immediately doing the
thing where he backs off, "You're
right." Soon as somebody challenges on
something, "You're completely right.
You're absolutely right. I was wrong."
He does that every time. Check it out.
>> So, here's what's interesting. You told
Joe Rogan last October,
quote, "Call me crazy, [music]
but I think that if there's going to be
peace with Iran, Donald Trump is going
to make that peace with Iran." Can I
call you crazy now?
>> Yeah, yeah, call me crazy.
>> [music]
>> I I
>> You got it wrong.
>> I was I was totally wrong.
>> And it wasn't just you. A lot of people
thought Trump was going to be anti-war.
I met Muslim friends of mine who said,
"Trump's going to be anti-war. Kamala
Harris is a neocon. Joe Biden's a
Zionist. Trump's going to be anti-war."
And it's turned out that the guy has
attacked what, seven countries last
year? He did Venezuela at the start of
this year. He's done Iran, and now
apparently Cuba any day now.
How did you get it wrong?
>> I really believed that
that
>> [music]
>> I really believed that he really
believed he had a chance of winning the
Nobel Peace Prize.
>> [music]
>> Yeah, so he says that at the time he
thought that Trump would, you know,
facilitate peace with Iran because he
wanted the Peace Prize. I mean, maybe. I
don't know if that's the case that he
made on Joe Rogan, but uh that seems a
little different from saying that like
this is a guy who has an anti-war plan
because he knows, Kiriakou knows just as
well as anybody that any president is
going to walk in there and face the same
pressures. He talks about that in this
interview [music] that the CIA is going
to try to sweeten you up and get you on
their side in terms of what they're
doing so that they can manipulate you
essentially. So, of course they're going
to do that to Trump. And after a full
Trump administration, we could see that
they had already done that the first
time and that his actions were aligning
with what they would have wanted by the
end of his first presidency much more
than at the beginning. So, that's where
this thing he says, you know, I
essentially bought that Trump really
meant it when he said he was anti-war.
And I just don't buy that. I don't see
how a person who has has the experience
that he has from the inside and has the
political beliefs that he says he has
would have bought into that. Although,
he wouldn't be the only person that's in
government or somewhere in like the
scientific institutions that kind of
came to the same conclusion, got sort of
sci-op'd the same way. But, there's
something about it that just seems,
again, a little bit overly agreeable.
And [music] here is where he says what
his political beliefs are supposedly,
and this is where I kind of believe him,
but also am struggling to see the
consistency a little bit.
>> yourself as a third generation Democrat
who left the party ages ago. I think you
were once [music] vice president of the
college Dems at GW prior to being
recruited.
What made you leave the Democratic Party
and where do you stand on the political
spectrum? Now, how would you classify
your politics now to your new online
followers? You say you're conservative,
you're liberal, you're a socialist. What
are you?
>> I call myself a leftist libertarian.
>> Okay.
>> I also am a firm believer in the fact
that the ideological spectrum is not a
straight line from [music] left to
right, that it's a circle. And it meets
>> often used as a pejorative, that the
horseshoe, the far right and far left
meet.
>> [music]
>> Well, I but I think that's a good thing.
>> Okay.
>> I I'm perfectly happy to cooperate
[music] with somebody like Marjorie
Taylor Greene, for example, on an issue
like [music]
Jeffrey Epstein or Israel-Palestine,
Gaza, Iran, whatever. Perfectly happy to
take support from wherever I can find
it.
>> So, he does the horseshoe theory thing.
He also I kind of wish Manny had allowed
him to finish that cuz I've never heard
somebody describe it as a circle. I kind
of wonder what he was getting at. But
it's essentially the same thing where
you kind of meet back up with the far
left and the far right, blah, blah,
blah. I don't subscribe to that. Manny
correctly says that that's kind of a
pejorative used to discredit [music] any
type of actual anti-government action
and ideology that comes from the left.
So, that's why a guy like this should be
concerned and would well know after
being in the CIA taking part in sabotage
campaigns of all kinds of left-wing
projects. That's a big part of what the
CIA does, for sure. It's not part that
he talks about much, although sometimes,
but he should know that the, you know,
the sneaking in of right-wing ideology
into left-wing movements is one of the
ways that you destroy them. Whereas
coming from the right, you almost never
get any real reform of power. You never
get any actual critique of power because
all the right wants is to just take and
utilize power. They don't scale back
government, and certainly not the right
wing dictators that were installed by
the CIA. They didn't deliver on any
anti-corruption policy or anything like
that. [music] So, this idea that he's
just kind of affable to the idea of the
American right is the biggest pill that
I can't swallow with this guy. Like,
there's zero skepticism of people like
Tucker Carlson and this like fake right
wing populist movement in America. And
if anybody knows what that sort of thing
smells like, it's a [__] CIA guy. So,
if he was really being honest, he would
be calling that out. Instead, he's
encouraging us to ally with people like
Tucker Carlson, right wingers, etc. And
here in this last part, Medhi calls him
out about his previously having endorsed
James Fishback, who is a Republican
candidate, I think, for governor in
Florida. Just virulently racist groper,
Nazi type this guy is, but disguised
with anti-Israel, anti-Zionist policies.
So, here's Medhi confronting him about
that.
>> I need to talk about someone else,
because I was looking forward to this
interview. My team and I did some
research, and then I got very upset.
>> Uh-oh.
>> So, I've got a bone to pick with you.
>> Okay.
>> You endorsed in Florida the far right
Republican candidate James [music]
Fishback, who is very anti-Israel, very
anti-establishment, claims to be a
libertarian. He's also a brazen racist.
>> Yeah, I didn't endorse him.
>> Okay.
>> I and and I'm not using this as an
>> "Listen, if you're a Republican voting
for governor of Florida, consider James
Fishback." February 2026, that was you.
>> Yeah, that was my assistant.
And I tore him a new one for for a week.
>> John, live with Ted Rall.
>> Oh, no, I know what you're talking
about. Oh, yes. [music] And that was a
stupid thing to say. I didn't really
know anything about him other than I had
seen this clip.
>> I thought you were going to say, "Aaron,
defend James Fishback to me," and then
we would have had a real falling out.
>> this clip where he's yelling about
AIPAC, and I said, "Hey,
>> of people A lot of people There's a
problem with the clips, though.
>> Yeah, and then
>> You got to be careful with the clips.
>> And then my assistant endorsed him on
Twitter, and I had to delete it. And I
was like, "No,
>> So, just to be clear, so if you ask me,
he just straight-up instinctually lies
here. The first thing he says is that I
never endorsed him. So, he's talking
about this tweet that went out that he
apparently deleted, and he immediately
says that was my assistant. [music] Not
buying that. But, then Medhi says,
"Wait, you said this on a live show."
And he did. So, he is quoting John
Kiriakou here saying that any Republican
in Florida should consider voting for
Fishback. Again, virulent racist, like
absolutely horribly racist. He said he
only saw a clip of him talking about
AIPAC. Okay, fair enough. But, if the
tweet went out after that because your
assistant thought you were endorsing
him,
>> [music]
>> first of all, that raises some questions
on its own about who exactly your
assistant is, but why wouldn't you
remember that you originally said it in
the first place, which was supposedly
why your assistant tweeted out? Cuz if
your assistant just tweeted it out of
their own volition, that's a little
suspicious on its own, isn't it, Mr. CIA
officer? So, I think he kind of just
like throws out a couple lies there,
then remembers what Medhi's talking
about, gives the answer on that. And
again, I think this is just him
agreeing. He's just like, "You're right,
I never should have done that. I was
totally wrong, totally wrong. You're
right, Medhi." And he did the same thing
on PBD, where PBD confronted him,
ironically, about Tucker Carlson.
Thought Tucker Carlson might have said
something to Kiriakou about how PBD is a
Zionist, which he is. But, Kiriakou
didn't say, "Well, you are a Zionist,
and I think this, and I think that." He
just said, "You're right." He said, "I'm
not going to say whose whose name it
was, but you're right. You're right, and
I was wrong. I was totally wrong for
ever implying that you're a Zionist."
Even though he was right about that.
apparently was just, you know, saying
that cuz that's what he thought of PBD
at the time. Uh and then just completely
backed off it. So, I'm not seeing a guy
here who believes in much of anything,
but to the extent that he does, I mean,
he's completely bought into this brown
shirt, red shirt alliance thing. And
[music] to me, that just seems like an
op. And, you know, I feel like him and
Tucker Carlson seem like they have a
similar project at the moment, which is
to ingratiate themselves uh to the left,
and also, you know, attack Israel, and
defend other interests in the Middle
East. So, the attacking Israel part is
great, but I think, you know, the tie
between the white supremacy and [music]
the right-wing approach to attacking
Israel is really the key here. And
especially as we're seeing like pogroms
happening in [__] Ireland, not
towards Jewish people, but towards
immigrants.
>> [music]
>> And, you know, whatever leftism Kiriakou
has, it's not geared towards justice for
immigrants. I'm sure he would agree with
that position if he was talking to a
left-winger. But, that's not what he's
advocating for. And instead, he's
allying with Tucker Carlson and
encouraging us to do the same. So, that
does not lead me to think that his
intentions are to see a more positive
left-wing politics in America. And for
now, I'll leave it at that.